<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts from Chen Wang</title><link>https://chenwang.org/</link><description>Recent content on Thoughts from Chen Wang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2012-2022 Chen Wang | Built by &lt;a href='https://github.com'>GitHub&lt;/a> and &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> with &lt;a href='https://github.com/natarajmb/charaka-hugo-theme'>Charaka theme&lt;/a> | &lt;a href='https://github.com/cwang/cwang.github.io'>Source Code&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chenwang.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise | Part V: Other Strategic Topics</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p5/</guid><description>(^ Mission Zero - How? ^)
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about strategies. Jesse, one of the VCs who invested in Wise explained why he thought Wise was built to last. I am equally bullish and agree with the reasons listed, a lot of which have been covered in earlier parts of this series. Here I look at a few other topics.
Fiscally responsible and disciplined Anybody working at Wise would have remembered Matt’s frequent appearances on the biweekly team call, talking about everything finance.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise | Part IV: The Engineering Organisation</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p4/</guid><description>(^ Hackathon 2018 | Conversion Team in action among others - Daniel, Karl, Urgo &amp;amp; Michael ^)
It would have been a waste of opportunity NOT to talk specifically about the engineering organisation at Wise, as this is a topic close to my heart. I could not have had a better learning experience living and breathing the changes in those years when the organisation reacted to the growing demand.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise | Part III: All about People</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p3/</guid><description>(^ TransferWise Summer Days 2019 ^)
I care deeply about people, equally so when I was at Wise, surrounded by a group of kind and motivated human beings.
Culture shapes people who in turn make culture I spend Part I and II covering many cultural aspects at Wise. I was curious about the early culture and its evolvement because I was not there in the beginning. The common response, when I asked this question to various people across functional areas, was that it did not change much.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise | Part II: Autonomy in the DNA</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p2/</guid><description>(^ Autonomous team growth, 2012 - 2021 ^)
To me, the culture of Wise was anchored on two foundations: feedback and autonomy. Jessica had a good writeup on the former already. I’d like to single out autonomy which had a profound impact on how Wise operated.
I am a big fan of autonomy and its application at Wise. Towards the latter part, I look at the areas where autonomy may fall short and offer my opinions on those areas.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise | Part I: Mission and Values</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p1/</guid><description>(^ Kristo &amp;amp; Taavet, 2014 ^)
I used to think of mission as corporate-speak, before joining Wise. I was sceptical about Wise’s mission and values in the beginning too. Later on, seeing how concrete strategies were put in place to achieve the mission, I was convinced.
I may be full of praise in this part which is unlike myself, but that is my true reflection.
A true mission attracts and motivates people “money without borders – instant, convenient, transparent and eventually free” was (and still is) the mission.</description></item><item><title>Hacking (Engineering) Hiring</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-07-hacking-engineering-hiring/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-07-hacking-engineering-hiring/</guid><description>Since offering my free advice session, engineering hiring has been the No. 1 topic people ask about. It inspired this article.
One question I always ask myself when hiring is what can we do beyond covering common hygiene factors, knowing that it only keeps you afloat but not winning the talent war.
These are actionable items for tech or tech-enabled startups and scale-ups going through rapid growth, resulting in the (urgent) need to make (large number of) engineering hires to support product development.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned in 10 years of Volcube</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2021-02-volcube-10-years-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2021-02-volcube-10-years-series/</guid><description>I vividly remember the early summer of 2010, when I started writing code for a stealth-mode startup. There was no name but we used a code name “project volt”. Fast forward 10 years, Volcube, as it later became known, was sold to our joint venture partner of 5 years.
Looking back, I count myself lucky as 90% of the startups fail; We managed to build a leading product in the field from scratch, with a number of customer segments spanning many countries.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned in 10 years of Volcube | Part III: AOB (any other business)</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2021-01-volcube-10-years-p3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2021-01-volcube-10-years-p3/</guid><description>Co-Founders: trust and complementary skills I am grateful to have Simon as the co-founder and CEO of the business. He did everything: coming up with the idea, making big or small product decisions, even writing some code in questionable quality and most importantly, making sales. I had the easy part: building it. Having complementary skills is clearly helpful from the start.
We did not know each other prior to Volcube.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned in 10 years of Volcube | Part II: Engineering &amp; Design</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2021-01-volcube-10-years-p2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2021-01-volcube-10-years-p2/</guid><description>Engineering: take on technical debt options and make lucky guesses Volcube is all about trading options and I think it is a closer metaphor than debt in making engineering trade-offs. Debt will have to be repaid; options can be taken up but there is no obligation. It could be useful taking a step back to imagine a product 1/3/5 years down the line, and what would be required engineering-wise that current design would make amends.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned in 10 years of Volcube | Part I: Product &amp; Growth</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2021-01-volcube-10-years-p1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2021-01-volcube-10-years-p1/</guid><description>Product: (the small) addressable market size Volcube was the best product in the space it occupies, which was a market-making trading simulation and education for financial options. This may sound like a boast but let me point out the fact that it is in such a niche market, which is combined with another fact that we did well in bringing a good idea into reality. Here comes the biggest learning though: always target a market with large addressable size.</description></item><item><title>Opinionated Patterns/Practices in Java Development and Deployment, 2017 Edition</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2017-03-java-dev-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2017-03-java-dev-deploy/</guid><description>Caveat Java and JVM have changed a lot since this article was written.
Read with a nostalgic lens.
Development In general Use Java 8 and use it well Use an IDE and use it well Prefer Enum over defined constant/variable Prefer standard/built-in exceptions over custom/user-defined ones Almost always use java.util.concurrent and its subpackages instead of Thread/Runnable Use Interface only when it is absolutely necessary Use Package structure wisely to avoid spaghetti code Master a build tool and stick to it For application developers Choose libraries/frameworks wisely (but still prefer the use of libraries/frameworks over BYO) Write your code so that it can be as framework-agnostic as possible (or if a framework is to be used, embrace it and its dependencies whole-heartedly) Write meaningful tests, i.</description></item><item><title>JSR-223 Java Scripting API - a Real World Use Case: Success and Pitfalls</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2012-09-java-scripting-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2012-09-java-scripting-api/</guid><description>Despite the fact that Java 6 is fast approaching EOL, certain newly added features seem to still remain relatively unknown or unused; JSR-223, the Java Scripting API is probably one of those least mentioned in “What’s New in Java 6” type articles. In this article, we will touch on a real-world use case of the new API and its programming model. Hopefully towards the end, the readers can have a better understanding of the feature and form their own opinions about the suitability for use of the API in their own projects.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://chenwang.org/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/about/</guid><description>What this site is for I started writing more a few years ago (speaking too), perhaps as a result of realising how scalable it is as a communication channel.
The content here are reflections on my experience, some technical others managerial. The common theme is software engineering in tech startup/scale-up environment.
My intention is to let readers re-live my experience (and re-think my mistakes too) in order for them to reflect on in their mindspace.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://chenwang.org/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/contact/</guid><description>Ask away I am open for various opportunities.
Send your request here
Book free advice session Starting from 2022, I offer advice sessions every week to just about anybody as my way of paying it forward.
Book yours here</description></item><item><title>Media Appearances</title><link>https://chenwang.org/appearances/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/appearances/</guid><description>Here are some of my guest appearances, covering topics I care about such as software engineering, hiring, leadership and startup.
JUN 2022 | Cord | Video - YouTube As part of Best Work Stories series, Ben (Cord CEO) and I talked about my journey from bootstrapping to Wise to VC backed startup.
MAY 2022 | Cord | Video - YouTube As part of Start-up Life series, I answered the question how does bootstrapping shape a start up.</description></item></channel></rss>