<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise on Thoughts from Chen Wang</title><link>https://chenwang.org/series/reflections-on-3-years-of-transfer-wise/</link><description>Recent content in Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise on Thoughts from Chen Wang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2012-2022 Chen Wang | Built by &lt;a href='https://github.com'>GitHub&lt;/a> and &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> with &lt;a href='https://github.com/natarajmb/charaka-hugo-theme'>Charaka theme&lt;/a> | &lt;a href='https://github.com/cwang/cwang.github.io'>Source Code&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chenwang.org/series/reflections-on-3-years-of-transfer-wise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise | Part III: All about People</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p3/</guid><description>(^ TransferWise Summer Days 2019 ^)
I care deeply about people, equally so when I was at Wise, surrounded by a group of kind and motivated human beings.
Culture shapes people who in turn make culture I spend Part I and II covering many cultural aspects at Wise. I was curious about the early culture and its evolvement because I was not there in the beginning. The common response, when I asked this question to various people across functional areas, was that it did not change much.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise | Part II: Autonomy in the DNA</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p2/</guid><description>(^ Autonomous team growth, 2012 - 2021 ^)
To me, the culture of Wise was anchored on two foundations: feedback and autonomy. Jessica had a good writeup on the former already. I’d like to single out autonomy which had a profound impact on how Wise operated.
I am a big fan of autonomy and its application at Wise. Towards the latter part, I look at the areas where autonomy may fall short and offer my opinions on those areas.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on 3 years of (Transfer) Wise | Part I: Mission and Values</title><link>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenwang.org/posts/2022-08-wise-3-years-p1/</guid><description>(^ Kristo &amp;amp; Taavet, 2014 ^)
I used to think of mission as corporate-speak, before joining Wise. I was sceptical about Wise’s mission and values in the beginning too. Later on, seeing how concrete strategies were put in place to achieve the mission, I was convinced.
I may be full of praise in this part which is unlike myself, but that is my true reflection.
A true mission attracts and motivates people “money without borders – instant, convenient, transparent and eventually free” was (and still is) the mission.</description></item></channel></rss>